MARTIN BEDOYA

Full-Stack Web Developer

Phone: 281.513.8744 | Email: martin.bedoyarivera@nbcuni.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/martinbedoya87

GitHub: github.com/josemartin357

Portfolio: josemartin357.github.io/martin-bedoya-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in broadcast communications and newly acquired skills in front-end, back-end and database technologies. Effective at developing applications with high performance, while using storytelling knowledge to create a user-friendly experience. Known by peers for adaptability, self-motivation, analytical and teamwork skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js, JQuery, Handlebars.js, Bootstrap, Materialize.

Back-end: Express.js, Node.js, REST AP, Insomnia, Robo3T. **Database Management:** MySQL, MongoDB, IndexedDB.

Other: JSON, Git, Heroku, Github.

PROJECTS

LUX | github.com/josemartin357/LUX | lux-rentals.herokuapp.com

- Node-based app for a car rental business, in which users can browse and submit a reservation form. Used Model/View/Controller design.
- Responsibilities: Models and Routes.
- Technologies used: Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, Heroku.

GIFcast | github.com/josemartin357/GifCast | josemartin357.github.io/GifCast

- App displays the current weather data in a searched city, along with the +4 days forecast with a GIF using a weather rating function.
- Responsibilities: Fetch Open Weather Map API and HTML/CSS.
- Technologies used: JavaScript, Materialize CSS, Open Weather Map API and GIPHY API.

Techie Blog | github.com/josemartin357/Tech-notes | techie-blog-mb.herokuapp.com/

- CMS-style blog, where developers can publish their blog posts and comment on other developers' posts as well. Used MVC structure.
- Responsibilities: Created design, functions, routes, seeds, and models.
- Technologies used: Node.js, Express.js, MySql, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, Bootstrap, Heroku.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Producer NBC Universal

2017 – Current Dallas, TX

Create, write and manage newscasts and special projects. Lead and train personnel in communications/broadcasting skills. Handle crisis management and oversee project development.

Key Accomplishments:

- Emmy Awards for breaking news coverage and best newscast.
- Market leaders (Nielsen ratings) multiple times.

Producer NBC Universal 2015 - 2017 Houston, TX

Create, execute and manage news and web content (articles, galleries, videos).

Supervise reporters, anchors, photographers, and assignment desk editors.

Develop and manage various kinds of media forms to promote business objectives and a positive brand image.

Key Accomplishments:

- Increased ratings at 10 pm primetime and weekend shows.
- Various special projects were recognized with Emmy awards.

EDUCATION

Certificate | Full-Stack Web Development

Southern Methodist University, 2021-2022

Master of Arts | Media Management

University of Oklahoma, 2011 - 2014

Bachelor of Liberal Arts | Mass Communications

Univ. of Central Oklahoma, 2009 - 2010

Associate in Science | Business

Oklahoma City Community College, 2005 - 2007